The rules keep changing.
I've been rehearsing every possible outcome.
Once this thought arises, there is no more room for right or wrong.
I am resolved to sever this flood
so that my soul can break free from mediocrity,
from loneliness and distinction.
One more step and you'll fall into madness.
Don't fall down.
I look towards the top.
Chase !
Refined to perfection.
Never retreat, no matter the danger.
I dare to defy the heavens !
Always overcome the obstacles,
ignite the seas with blood,
bloom through trials and tribulations.
Even the sharpest thorns
will be reduced into ashes.
What is there to fear ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Insolent brat,
you will regret your recklessness !
Arrogant Junior,
how dare you harm an Elder of the Sun Family
and destroy our defensive formation !?
Sun Leng
Sun Family Elder
Peak Late stage
Soul Transformation
Sun Huan
Sun Family Elder
Peak Late stage
Soul Transformation
Sun Xu
Sun Family Elder
Peak Late stage
Soul Transformation
If you break your own arms and kneel in apology,
I will spare your life for now !
I met this Elder Sun through a transaction.
He obtained a flying sword and a bronze mirror
through a trade with me.
If you open his bag of holding,
you can verify what I said.
He coveted one of my artifacts
and tried to kill me for it.
After I drove him back,
he fled all the way here.
He's likely telling the truth...
But the Sun Family cannot tolerate a Junior running rampant !
No matter which family he is from,
we will capture him with the Demon Sealing Formation
and wait for his Elders
to decide whether he lives or dies !
Since you're doing this,
it seems the entire Sun Family is an accomplice.
What cultivation level does this child have !?
This pressure far exceeds Soul Transformation !
Could he be...
Fellow cultivator,
please calm your anger.
Sun Qiming
Sun Family Grand Elder
Peak Late stage Soul Transformation
Grand Elder !
Ascendant Divine Sense ?
The Sun Family has offended you, fellow cultivator.
We are willing to compensate for it.
Please tell us what you want, fellow cultivator.
Don't trouble my Juniors.
200 000 celestial jades
and this matter is settled.
Agreed.
But the amount you requested is too much.
We are only a branch of the Sun Family.
Fellow cultivator, please wait 3 days
to allow us to gather the celestial jades.
He agreed rather quickly...
If the Sun Family Ancestor is not magnanimous,
then he must have ulterior motives.
Agreed.
Giving 200 000 celestial jades at once
is a terrible loss
even for the main family !
The Ancestor personally ordered
to grant all his requests.
This is an order,
don't allow what happened today to leak.
And never disturb this person.
Anyone who causes trouble
will be immediately banished
until a decision is made.
Now that I have tens of thousands of celestial jades on me,
I need to absorb them all as soon as possible
to reach Middle stage Ascendant.
You...
Stop here.
Junior of the Sun Family...
If you dare to stir up trouble,
I will be merciless.
Do you know
what is most important for cultivation ?
Please enlighten me.
Let me tell you.
The most important is diligence !
Although you lack talent,
if you are diligent in your cultivation
you may still make progress one day.
I guard this Spirit Vein
and have seen many Core Formation, Nascent Soul and even Soul Formation cultivators.
But I have never seen anyone like you
that stops meditating to wander around the city in the morning.
The fiend usually kills without blinking an eye
but he's letting a Junior lecture him ?
This scene is probably a once-in-a-millennium event !
I must make sure to remember it !
Senior is right.
It’s not that I look down on you
but in this cultivation world
only the self-reliant can go far.
If you have any questions about cultivation in the future,
you may ask me about them.
Remember to be diligent in your cultivation.
Don't let you mind and body be lazy.
You may go in now.
Although this person’s cultivation is weak,
compared to the deceit and treachery of the Alliance Star System,
this isn't unpleasant.
3 days later
After reaching Ascendant,
cultivating with celestial jades
consumes too much...
Even with the Sun Family’s 200 000 celestial jades,
I won't reach Middle stage Ascendant.
To make a push for the second step,
the amount of celestial jades needed is unimaginable.
The Celestial Realm is no more.
Maybe what the second step requires is not celestial jades,
but something else.
Senior,
Sun Qiming of the Sun Family requests an audience.
The 200 000 celestial jades have been sent from the main family.
Please Senior, check them.
No need.
You may leave.
Our last meeting was too short.
Junior still does not know your honorable name.
Xu Mu
Senior,
In 7 days, an auction will be held
at the Whole Treasure Pavilion.
Among the items,
there will be a grade 8 pseudo-divine pill.
Senior,
this is the invitation to the auction.
Reveal the information about the grade 8 pill to this person
to test him.
This pill is extremely effective for Ascendant cultivators.
If he is interested,
then he is just Ascendant
and he will surely take it.
And if he is not interested ?
Then his cultivation is above Ascendant
and you
must withdraw the Sun Family’s forces from the city
to avoid any further involvement.
Give it to me.
This kind of test
will not happen a second time.
Understood.
You've come...
Sit down.
The Sun Family invited me to the auction.
This kind of test feels strange.
Is there something wrong ?
I can feel that
they are afraid of something.
Afraid ?
They are indeed living in fear and dread.
They
have brought a huge disaster upon themselves.
4 years ago,
in the space near Planet Ran Yun,
the Sun Family Ancestor, Sun Xi,
Carefree Xanren, Zhao Chuanwen,
and the Ran Family Ancestor, Ran Xuefeng,
joined forces
to ambush and kill a severely wounded cultivator who had fled here.
They obtained 5 pills.
5 grade 8 pseudo-divine pills.
But after the excitement,
inside that person's bag of holding
they found
a token from...
Planet Thousand Illusions.
A token of the Huan Family.
The Huan Family ?
Yes !
The very Huan Family of Planet Thousand Illusions, the leader of the Northern Domain.
Ceng Niu,
do you know how the Huan Family acts
and how overbearing they are ?
If a family member is killed,
all parties involved
no matter their identity,
will have their entire family exterminated.
Even if the items from the dead person’s bag end up in someone else’s hands,
merely possessing them
is likely to be seen as provocation
and trigger their wrath.
That token
and those pills
are all death sentences.
Once you’re stained by them, you can’t shake them off.
These past 4 years,
they have been walking on thin ice
and living in fear that one day
the Huan Family’s thunderous wrath
will come for them.
So this auction
is a bait
to hook me
in this karma with the Huan Family.
They're trying to put me in the same boat as them.
They want to atone for their crime
to avoid the extermination of their families
by framing you.
If the Huan Family investigates,
they will put all the blame on you.
Or at least,
they'll use you as an excuse.
What a clever scheme,
shifting the blame on others to have them do the dirty work.
Ran Xuefeng...
Sun Xi...
Zhao Chuanwen...
This matter will have too many consequences,
don't get involved.
Thank you.
A grade 8 pseudo-divine pill
would at least allow me to directly reach Middle stage Ascendant.
To reach Planet Dong Lin as soon as possible,
I must obtain this pill.
This trap might be sinister
but I must walk into it.
Huan Family Ancestral Home
Planet Thousand Illusions
That family member went missing 4 years ago.
Huan Wuqing
Huan Family Ancestor
Why are we only dealing with it now ?
Ancestor,
that person was merely a branch family member.
The Huan Family has many members
so they're hard to track.
Huan Fengshen
Huan Family Head
We have only learned of this matter recently.
Ancestor, how do you think
we should handle this matter ?
Now that we know,
we can't ignore it anymore.
All those involved
must be eradicated !
Leave this matter to Huan Mei.
Let her assign her own people to handle it.
It's a perfect opportunity
to have her establish authority.
As the Ancestor orders.
I shall take my leave.
Ever since the Ancestor went to the Alliance and brought back Huan Mei,
3 months ago
he stopped dealing with affairs of the family.
From now on,
Huan Mei will be this old man’s core disciple.
Now, the Ancestor went out of his way
to sacrifice his cultivation and use the blood exchange ritual on an outsider.
Now he's helping her establish her authority in the family...
Does he really intend to give the Huan Family
to this woman ?
Attic
Huan Family Ancestral Home
Planet Ran Yun ?
Huan Dong,
Huan Dong
Huan Family
Peak Middle stage Ascendant
I'm here.
Your cultivation has reached Peak Middle stage Ascendant.
This trip should be easy.
Although this is a minor matter,
it's my first task for the Huan Family.
It must be dealt with quickly.
Huan Dong,
do you understand ?
The strongest cultivator on Planet Ran Yun
is only at Middle stage Ascendant.
On this mission,
I will make sure to exterminate all those involved.
I will not tarnish your reputation !
You can go.
Understood !
Your subordinate takes his leave.
This matter must be handled splendidly
to win my lady’s favor.
East Sea
Planet Ran Yun
According to recent rumors among the Juniors,
this Xu Mu is a Thunder Celestial Messenger
and has some connection to Planet Dong Lin.
This person is truly unfathomable.
He has likely seen through our scheme
and will not show up.
How precious is
a grade 8 pseudo-divine pill ?
As an Ascendant,
who wouldn't go crazy for it ?
Since he took the invitation,
all we need to do
is to do everything we can
to make him win the pill.
The Thunder Celestial Temple and Planet Dong Lin
are just talk among Juniors.
They may be wrong.
We went through all this trouble
but if this person isn't strong enough,
and he ends up being useless when the Huan Family shows up,
Planet Ran Yun
will be doomed.
We can know what he's made of
with a simple test.
They've come.
With such pressure...
could it be one of the Ancestors ?
This person is here to cause trouble !
This residence is under my responsibility
and as long as you are in this courtyard,
I will ensure your safety !
Go back in.
You're no match for him.
Don’t worry about it !
Senior,
this place is a property of the Sun Family.
May I ask what business Senior has here ?
What's your name ?
Junior's name is Sun Ling.
You are very diligent.
You may back down now.
Senior,
as long as he is inside,
it's Junior's duty to protect him !
Besides,
he's only a Core Formation cultivator.
Why must Senior deal with him ?
This is...
Enough.
He was captured by that Senior...
He likely won’t survive.
I have done all I can...
Go !
This person’s cultivation
is very strong.
If he falls in the trap,
Planet Ran Yun will survive this calamity.
Fellow cultivator Xu,
I am Sun Xi.
I mean no harm to you,
please don't be offended.
The other day, you saved a junior of the Sun Family.
I have prepared a small gift for you.
It was not a big deal.
To be honest, fellow cultivator Xu,
the reason I have come
is to accompany you to the Whole Treasure Pavilion
to participate in the auction.
I wish you success and hope you will gain from it.
Sun Qiming greets the Ancestor.
Greetings, Senior Xu.
Please.
Since he already knows it's a trap,
why did he still risk coming ?
What background does this person have
to be standing beside the Ancestor ?
Brother Xu,
the final item of this auction is a grade 8 pill.
Its origin
is somewhat special.
This pill does not come from our Planet Ran Yun.
Fellow cultivator Sun,
I don’t like listening to stories.
Brother Xu,
if I don’t tell you this story,
I know that with Brother Xu's intelligence,
you will have some doubts about it.
Fellow cultivators,
the next item for auction is the final treasure of this event:
A grade 8 pseudo-divine pill !
This pill contains immense celestial spiritual energy
and can only be endured by Ascendant cultivators.
If anyone below Ascendant forcefully consumes it,
their body will explode.
Starting bid,
10 000 celestial jades !
The Sun Family has ordered
that the auction of this item
must not be interfered with.
The 3 family Ancestors are not using it themselves
but putting it for auction.
This matter is inherently suspicious...
Is there any bidder ?
If no fellow cultivator bids,
the auction for this pill will end
and the pill will be temporarily available for sell.
I will bid !
One celestial jade.
Reminder: Liu Mei's domain was the Thousand Illusions Ruthless domain that got transformed into the Thousand Illusions Lust Domain.
Huan means illusion.
"The glass-looking planet is planet Thousand Illusions. This is one of the five main planets of the Northern Domain of the Allheaven Star System. Mei'er, my Allheaven Star system cares a lot about bloodlines. Without the family bloodline, you won’t be able to practice higher level cultivation methods and won’t receive protection from the family.
"From now on, aside from being my disciple, you are also my adopted daughter. Once I return to planet Thousand Illusions, I’ll cast the blood exchange ritual to change your bloodline. From then on you will no longer be called Liu Mei but Huan Mei! Do you agree?
"Everything will go according to Master’s will."
"This trip to Allheaven Star System is a new life for me… Wang Lin and everything that happened on planet Suzaku are now in the past. With his talent, he probably hasn’t even reached the Ascendant stage yet. Also, it isn’t even certain whether he can pass the life and death trial when breaking into the Ascendant stage."
"He is probably still on planet Suzaku. Compared to me… he is no longer on the same level."
Ask
Qi Condensation
the perilous path filled with countless blades.
Foundation Establishment
Can the mundane world be shattered
Core Formation
Nascent Soul
by a child's steadfast heart ?
If the laws of this world
Soul Formation
Soul Transformation
stand in the way,
I'll defy the universe to tread the heavens
Ascendant
and ask this question to the sky.
My heart's deepest wish
is to not kneel before these mountains and rivers.
Don't accept your doomed fate,
karma can be changed.
Unwilling to let go,
my obsessions propel me forward.
Don't be afraid.
Thunder rumbles as I dare to tread through the reincarnation cycle.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.